









RAKESH P PRAJAPATI

Email: p.rakesh2525@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Work in an innovative and challenging environment to dedicate myself for work undertaken and utilize my efficiency at the fullest. Highly motivated, proactive and results-oriented individual holding a rich IT experience of 15 years in Network Infrastructure and security

PROFILE

Having an excellent capability of understanding as well as solving a problem using my analytical, quantitative and logical skills. Ability to work methodically and analytically in a quantitative problem-solving environment I am hard working and always anxious for acquiring knowledge from the sources around which helps me learning more in a small span of time. And a personality with gentleness, politeness and optimistic in nature and hold good communication and interpersonal skills.

Awareness of ITIL process and worked for more than 12 years in Advantmed ,Gujarat Gas Ltd, medusind, Adani

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Maintain, manage and ensure the availability of the client's Network Infrastructure components
- Monitoring Network Equipment's hardware failures interface status as per client's Policy.
- Monitoring network Equipment's operation LAN, WAN & Recording Important Parameters (device Availability CPU, Memory Utilization, Packet drops, hardware failures) as per Policy
- Checking and reviewing network Equipment's System logs, escalation in time if anything found abnormal.
- Vendor /OEM in case OF failures and Provide necessary support to resolve network Problems
- Record Keeping and network documentation as per client Policies and Procedures
- Breakdown and preventive Maintenance of network Equipment's in coordination with OEM and AMC vendors.
- BCP Planning for Network Services/Devices and Documentation of BCP/DR scenarios SOP
- Project support for Network domain
- Directly involve in Internal/External and VAPT audit and Implement Observations and Noncompliance as a part of audit.
- Lan, Wan, San, WLan, VPN management, ensuring the active port are working properly.
- Manage LAN Network of around 6000 Users.
- Manage 14 India or US Locations switches, Firewalls and Routers of Advantmed
- Manage 2 Data Centres (DC & DR) having core router, core L3 switch, L2 FEX, SAN switch, firewall, LLB devices, server and storage connectivity.
- Manage MPLS and IIL links of 17 locations, and coordinate with ISP vendor.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Having knowledge in Cisco Software system (IOS, IOS-XE, NX-OS etc)
- Having experience Nexus 9000 Switching, cisco FEX 2000 & which includes SAN 9000 switch physical Data Centre deployments, highly reliable continuous system operation, optimizing uptime.
- Knowledge of RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, MPLS.. Routing protocols
- Having hands on experience on router ISR, ISR-G2, ISR 4000, ASR 1K-X series.
- Having experience Next Generation Firewall (Check Point 5600) and (PALO-ALTO 3410) physical Data Centre deployments And manage.
- Having experience PALO ALTO Strata Cloud Manager Deployment and strata cloud manager thru configuration Palo alto firewall and manage (PALO-ALTO 3440,3410,1420,1410).
- Knowledge of Force point proxy manage, performance monitor and troubleshooting.
- Having Knowledge of Array 7200 (multi- talent) Link load balance.
- Also having experience in deploying various OEM NMS tools like Entuity, MotaData, NagiOS, WhatsApp Gold ,PRTG,Ops manager
- Prepare SOP, for IT Tasks i.e. PM Activity, Backup & Restore and maintain reference documentation for each SOP.
- Inventory Management.
- Can configure & troubleshoot IP SLA, VPN technology, Flex Netflow, SNMP, NAT, ACLs, Device security AAA with 802.1x (Radius, TACACS+, local), DHCP snooping, QoS, PBR, Redundancy protocol (HSRP, VRRP, GLBP), VRF.
- Device backup and firmware up gradation.
- Implement and tshoot SVI, Trunking, Ether channel, STPs, Stack, VSS, ACL.
- Having experience Centre deployments Proxy ,firewall ,LTM And WLC

Router and switch

- CISCO ISR: -4000, ASR: -1000 And 1900
- CISCO NEXUS 9000, MDS:-9000, Catalyst:-9500, 9300, 3800 and 2900
- DELL:-2000, Net gear:- 2000

Performance through firewall model number

- Check point:-5600
- FortiGate:- 40C, 60D, 80C,90c
- WatchGuard:-200,330,830C
- Cisco ASA:-5520
- Palo alto :- PA3440,PA 3410,PA1410,PA1420,PA440

Link Load Balancer

- ARRAY 7200
- •
- Wireless controller
- Cisco 5505 and FortiGate 1000
- PROXY
- Force point 5000

<u>Have experience in implementing Router Switches, firewall configuration in the following</u> Companies.

- Ahmedabad Smart City
- Adani Pvt Ltd.
- Gujarat Gas Ltd.
- Advantmed.
- Medusind

PROJECT ACTIVITY

- Implemented Palo Alto Strata Cloud Manager and also SCM Thru all Paloalto firewall migration, configuration activity done.
- Implemented And migrated Firewall (SonicWALL to Palo alto) successfully in USA Datacentre and other 7 US for advantmed.
- Implemented Successfully 600 + users New office Setup at Visnagar Infocity tw1 And Pune Location
- Implemented Successfully CALL centre Network in Shillong location for medusind.
- Successfully moved all DC Network Devices for collocated Primary Data Canter.
- Implemented successfully BGP ECMP between Primary and Secondary MPLS service provider along with Active-Active + Auto fail over scenario for 70+ location across India.
- Successfully done upgrade of DC network L3 Switch 4506 to replace NEXUS 9000 L3 Switch at Surat (GGL) location.
- Successfully performed auto failover and redundancy (MPLS link, ILL link, Router, L3 Switch and check point firewall) DC network at GIFTCITY for Gujarat Gas Ltd.
- Successfully done Dell Chassis server to EMC 5300 and 5400 storage, HP and Dell tape library connectivity and zoning in Cisco MDS Switch.
- Successfully performed upgrade of campus network L3 SWITCH 4507 to replace 3800 L3 switch and cisco 300 to 2960x switch at Gujarat Gas Surat Location.
- Successfully deployed core HA check point firewall (5600) in DC and DR for Gujarat Gas.
- Successfully deployed Array HA LLB (7200) In DC and DR for Guiarat Gas.
- Have established and configured Force point proxy.
- Successfully integrated bsnl mpls link, router, L3 switch and fortigate firewall in DC, DR network at Ahmedabad smart city via company Trimax Smart Infra.
- Deployed Ahmedabad Smart City DC/DR project in which we design, implemented and tested the device are as follow:
 - 1. About 6000 surveillance cameras across the city.
 - 2. Parking Solution, VMD, e-challan software solution provided to Govt. entity.
 - 3. Also implied around 1500 wireless access point across the Ahmedabad city (Govt. Hospital, Govt. College, BRTS, public garden, Govt. AMC premises).
- Have done configuration 42 Routers 1941 and 10 ASR Router in IOS upgrade at Adani.
- Configured GRE tunnel, IP sec tunnel in all new MPLS TCL links at Adani.
- I have done configuration of Ring topology in 28 switches successfully at Dahej Adani Port to explore redundancy and also configured RSTP Protocols.
- Deployed 20 switches in the Ring topology at Adani house.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Present Status (2023):

Company : Advantmed india LLP

Designation : Sr.Firewall and Network L3 Engineer

OCT 2022 to April 2023):

Company : Medusind solutionDesignation : L3 Network Engineer

JAN 2019 TO SEP 2022:

Company : Allied Digital Services Itd

• Client : Gujarat Gas Ltd (Gandhinagar-Gujarat)

Designation : L3 Network Engineer

MAY 2018 to JAN 2019:

Company : WIPRO Ltd.

• Client : Gujarat Gas Ltd (Ahmedabad-Gujarat)

Designation : L3 Network Engineer

NOV 2017 to APRIL 2018:

Company : Trimax Smart Infra Projects Pvt. Ltd.

Client : Ahmedabad Smart CityDesignation : L3 Network Engineer

OCT 2016 to OCT 2017:

Company : Trimax IT Infrastructure& Service Ltd.
 Client : Gujarat Gas. Ahmedabad-Gujarat

• Designation : L3 Network Engineer

AUG 2014 to APRIL 2016:

Company : IMSI Pvt. Ltd.

Client : Adani Enterprise Ahmedabad-Gujarat

• Designation : Network Engineer

JULY 2013 to AUG 2014:

Company : Cps connect Technology Brand store
 Client : Cps connect Technology Brand store

• Designation : Sr. Technical Engineer

FEB 2012 to JUNE 2013:

Company : Chaque Jour HR Services Pvt Ltd.

Client : Torrent PowerDesignation : Technical Engineer

CERTIFICATIONS

CCNA (21-Aug-2012):- Cisco Certified Network Associate.

ID. No -CSCO12220684

FORTIGATE: - NSE 1 (8-MAY-2018) :-

ID: - P5UJATEJFT

FORTIGATE: - NSE 2 (17-OCT-2020):-

ID: - zkFAoHvBGA

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION			
Educational	School/College	Board/University	Year
B.COM	GLS IC	Gujarat University	2011
HSC	Jay Ambe School	GHSEB	2008
SSC	Amar Jyoti School	GSEB	2006

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 25-08-1990

Permanent Address: 5 Hemedra park soc opp jethabhai vav vatva Road, Ishanpur. Ahmedabad

Father's Name : Panchaji P Prajapati

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian

Linguistic Proficiency: English, Hindi, Gujarati, Marwadi

RAKESH P PRAJAPATI Contact Number: - 8511123546